This concludes the data
on Ayanokoji Kiyotaka
and the other 156 members
of the second-year class.
Have you memorized all of it?
Your role is to have Ayanokoji-kun
expelled within the month of April,
and return him to the White Room.
Be careful and clever in
your pursuit of this goal.
If this becomes known,
the name of that person...
of Sensei could be greatly damaged.
You seem displeased about this.
You don't think he deserves to
be treated as our masterpiece?
Well, I've set the stage for you.
Let me see what you can do.
With talent like yours, it should
be easy to get him expelled.
I forgot to ask one thing...
You're not hiding anything
from me, are you?
A battle between students
of the White Room—
Hunt or be hunted.
Though it's merely a
game between children,
it could prove interesting.
#1 Assassin From the White Room
Hey, they turned the blackboard
into a computer screen!
That's pretty cool!
Hey, Ayanokoji.
Miyake.
You didn't come to group meetings
much over spring break.
I was worried.
I'm sorry. I was a bit busy.
Obviously, you're under
no obligation to come,
but Haruka, and especially Airi,
seemed to miss you.
Sorry.
I'll try to show up
more often from now on.
Hope so.
I like having you there, too.
What were you talking about?
Nothing.
S-Suzune?!
What's with the hair?!
Horikita-san, this is quite a new you!
Is it that unusual to see
someone cut their hair?
N-Nah, I mean, I just didn't expect it.
It actually looks pretty
great on you, too...
R-Right, Kushida?
Yes, of course.
But what led you to do it?
You may consider it a display
of resolve, I suppose.
As we enter our second year, I intend
to fight to raise Class D's ranking.
I am prepared to do whatever
it takes to make that happen.
Oh, gotcha.
Maybe I'll grow my hair
out to balance it out!
There's a lot of noise in here.
Take your seats at once.
I'd like to start by asking you to
undergo a task crucial to your
lives here moving forward.
I want you to access the school's
homepage and install a new app.
The app's official name
is "Over All Ability."
OAA for short.
An application to assess and rank all students in the following five categories:
Academic Achievement: Primarily reflects written test scores across the year.
Physical Ability: Reflects evaluations in gym class, club activities, and special tests.
Situational Thinking: Reflects social proficiency, communication skills, and situational adaptability as
reflected in size of friend groups and position within them.
Prosocial Proficiency: Reflects contributions toward school community, including in-class attitude,
attendance, lack of problematic behavior, and student council affiliation.
General Evaluation: A reflection of the student's all-around ability calculated based on the four values
listed above (Prosocial Proficiency only counts half).
*General Evaluation =
(Academic Achievement + Physical Ability + Situational Thinking + Prosocial Proficiency*0.5) / 350 * 100 (rounded)
OAA?
This app will be used by
students in all years,
and it will provide you access
to a variety of resources.
For instance, individual
data on all students.
Have a look at your own data for starters.
T-Teacher!
It's giving me letter
ranks like in a game!
That's right.
These are individual assessments of
your abilities made by the school
based on your performance last year.
You can view the abilities of
students in all years and classes.
I'm an E in academic achievement?
The ratings will be updated at
the beginning of each month.
Sudo, even if you're rated E right now,
if you were to ace your next written
test, you would be ranked an A+.
But a bad score will also linger
as a blot on your record.
And everyone in the school
will be able to see it.
Remember that your first-year
ratings simply represent the past.
They won't affect your
evaluations moving forward.
We hope that those with less than
stellar marks will find new drive
to attempt to improve them.
A convenient tool to check
our accomplishments...
No, there's surely more to it than that.
This app represents equality.
We hope that being judged
on the same benchmarks will promote
more interaction between class years.
However...
I believe there's more to it than that.
This is just my own hypothesis,
but I suspect that anyone
whose General Evaluation does not meet a
certain benchmark by the end of the year
will face some kind of penalty.
Penalty? You mean... expulsion?
A-Are you kidding me?!
I'm sure some of you may not
be happy with your numbers,
but it's an evaluation of
your current standings.
If you don't like it,
spend this year forcing the school
to accept your true talents.
So we're fighting for ourselves.
The integration of this
app turns the concept
of fighting together
as a class on its head.
Their fear and confusion
is understandable.
In addition, this system
was adopted on the proposal
of the current student council
president, Nagumo Miyabi.
Create a system where we're evaluated
based on individual ability.
Nagumo's putting his dream into reality.
And your first special
test of your second year
will include an unprecedented concept.
You will partner up with the
incoming class of first-years
to take a written test.
Partner up with the first-years?
Previously, the school hasn't encouraged
interaction between class years.
We've deduced that this has hindered your
development of communication skills.
B-But aren't we competing with
other classes in our year?
It feels kinda weird, yeah.
Think about it.
When you enter the real world,
you won't always be interacting with
people from your graduating class.
And you may end up in competition with
first-years and third-years at times.
You can work with anyone from
any class in the first year.
The test will be at the end
of the month in two weeks.
You'll have plenty of time
to pick your partner.
We haven't interacted
with the first-years.
It will be difficult to build up a
relationship of trust from nothing.
Perhaps that's part of
what the OAA app is for.
The test will cover five subjects,
with a maximum score of 500 points.
And this is very important—
this time around, there will be
incentives for success on both class
and individual levels.
I knew it. If you fail, you're expelled!
Partnerships must be
formed by mutual consent,
and once decided,
cannot be undone for any reason.
I'm sure you've already realized that
academically proficient students will
be in high demand for this test.
Ma'am, what will happen to students who
can't find a partner before the test?
The leftovers will be paired
randomly on the day of the test.
That said,
a 5% penalty will be imposed on those who
failed to find a partner on their own.
So you're in deep trouble
if you don't find a partner!
Wh-Wh-What do we do, Hirata?!
Who the heck in year one is
gonna pair with someone
with an E in Academic Achievement?!
I'm worried, too.
Calm down, everyone.
Let's figure out our approach.
Yes, there's no need to hurry.
The app sent us something along
with the test conditions.
It's the predicted points for each
Academic Achievement rating.
The baseline for expulsion is 500
points between you and your partner.
Someone with an E-level
Academic Achievement
can work with someone of rank B or
higher and easily clear the test.
Horikita-san is right.
If we work hard to prepare like always,
I'm sure we can all get
through this again.
The most important thing is to be
careful when choosing partners.
If you encounter any issues,
talk to me or Hirata-kun.
Any student of any year found to be
intentionally lowering their score
will be expelled immediately.
That would normally be a
significant deterrence.
But it won't apply to
the White Room student.
If they manage to pair up with me,
they won't hesitate to score a
zero to take me down with them.
In other words, if I choose the person
from the White Room as my partner,
I'm done for.
Acting Chairman Tsukishiro...
I'm sure he came up with these rules.
Special Academic Test Outline.pdf
Class Incentives
-Class score is determined from the average score of all class members and their partners.
-Classes will be awarded the following class point totals based on their class score,
from highest to lowest: 50 points, 30 points, 10 points, 0 points.
Individual Incentives
-Individual score is the combined score of an individual and their partner.
-The top five pairs will receive a reward of 100,000 private points each.
-The top 30% of pairs will be given 10,000 private points each.
-If any pair scores a total of 500 or less, the second-year student will be expelled,
and the first-year student will not receive private points for three months
regardless of class point standings.
- Students found to be intentionally getting questions wrong to manipulate
or lower scores will be immediately expelled. Students found to be coercing
third parties into getting low scores will be likewise expelled.
Do you remember our agreement
over winter break,
that the two of us would compete?
You think the upcoming special
test is perfect for that?
Yes. If you win,
I'll join the student council.
If I win, you will henceforth use
all of the talent you've been hiding
for the sake of our class.
I have no objections.
Good.
Let's move to our next topic, then.
I looked into first-year students
with an Academic Achievement
rating of B or higher.
There are seventeen in Class A,
thirteen each in Class B and C,
and eleven in Class D.
Fifty-four in total.
We have only four students with
an Academic Achievement of E.
Twelve if we throw in those with D.
There are more than enough first-year
students to fill the roles we need.
The question is how to get such
excellent students to partner with
students ranked D or E.
Yes. I think Sudo-kun should
be our first priority.
Hasn't his Academic Achievement
been improving a lot?
It has.
But if you'd never met either of them before,
which would you rather pair with?
Sudo-kun or Ike-kun?
True. Sudo is physically imposing,
sharp-tongued, and generally frightening.
Yes. Finding him a partner
at all may prove difficult.
So I want to begin right away.
Will you help me?
Ichinose Honami
I've gotten permission to host a mixer between first-
and second-year students in the gym today starting at 4.
If you have time, we'd love to meet with you.
Ichinose-san is impressive, as always.
She's thinking not just of Class B,
but the entire picture at once.
Class A and Class C will likely
take their own measures.
I still don't know what Ryuen-kun
and Sakayanagi-san will try.
But I think one potential avenue for
negotiation would be private points.
You think we should attempt to bribe them?
Yes, points are the most obvious
asset we can offer to first-years.
Ideally, we would donate
our personal funds
to secure a certain number of students...
But with our lower point incomes,
it will be hard to play the money game.
I'll scout out the situation
at the mixer first.
Understood. I'll come along.
Oh? You're cooperating, then?
I just want to see how you
plan to approach this.
I see. I was hasty in using
the word "cooperate."
Her first impulse is
to build mutual trust.
That's rather typical of Ichinose-san.
But shouldn't we get down there, then?
What if Class B takes
all the smart people?
Do you think we could beat
Ichinose-san's team in a
competition of social graces?
It seems unlikely.
Let's go.
You sure about this, Suzune?
More than half of the students
didn't attend the mixer.
I want to speak to those who didn't.
Didn't you notice?
There's a bias among the
students attending the mixer.
Bias?
There were no students from Class 1-D.
Izzat supposed to mean something?
There are forty students in each class.
The fact that not a single one of them
attended suggests their
class is acting as a unit.
In other words, Class 1-D
already has a leader,
and they decided to blow off the mixer.
Yes.
If we can negotiate
directly with that leader,
we won't need to deal with individuals.
Hey. Ichinose's up to her old tricks, huh?
She seems to be focused first on saving
her classmates and first-years.
You think she realizes it's
a drag to help out idiots?
It's basically throwing in the towel.
Your Class A... Sakayanagi-san
anticipated this, didn't she?
That's why you didn't participate.
Yeah, I'd wager so.
So how do you intend to bring
the smart students to your side?
That's up to Her Highness.
I merely do as I'm told.
Let's hurry.
The Class D students should still
be in their classroom at this time.
You're pretty late to the party, Suzune.
Ryuen-kun.
You also went to scout out the first-years
instead of attending the mixer?
The only ones going to the gym
would be the class idiots.
I didn't need to look.
You've already been to Class D?!
Don't worry.
I haven't won anyone over yet.
Your attitude would just
frighten the first-years.
I think a few light threats will
get them on my side immediately.
You must be joking.
You think that method would be allowed?
Can't imagine why it wouldn't be.
I didn't see a rule saying you're
expelled for threatening someone
into being your partner.
It doesn't require a specific rule.
If someone complains,
you're the one who'll be affected.
Complain and see what happens, then.
Of course, I'm not so stupid
as to leave tracks behind.
I'll give you a piece of info, though...
Despite having just arrived,
the first-years are extremely composed.
What are you getting at?
There's a very good chance
that someone from the school
has already explained to the
newcomers how the school works.
Well, good luck engaging with them.
The first-years might be more resistant
to our efforts than expected.
All the more reason to
start negotiations now!
What the hell is this?!
Their class may be more difficult
to deal with than anticipated.
Notifications suggest that twenty-two
pairs have formed as of this morning.
If I draw the White Room spy,
I'm expelled on the spot.
I've memorized the names and faces of
all the first-years just in case, but...
Hey!
Some first-years are heading our way!
I'm Nanase Tsubasa of Class 1-D.
And this is my classmate...
Hosen.
Freshmen don't usually come to an
upperclassman's floor uninvited.
I respect your boldness.
You respect it, huh?
You think you're better than us?
Get your head outta your
ass, freshman punk.
He's Academic Achievement E+.
You're as dumb as you look, then, huh?
What was that?!
Figures, though. Class D are probably
the only ones who'd come out to meet us.
That suits us fine.
What is that supposed to mean?
Your Class D's a group of failures.
You're not gonna make any decent
pairings unless we come to you.
So since you're all stupid and useless,
we figured we'd lend a helping hand.
You get what I'm saying, right?
You want us to partner with you, then?
That's quite a presumptuous way of asking.
You're the ones who should be asking.
Go on, get on all fours and
beg us to pair up with you.
You bastard—
You seem to be under a misapprehension.
As a fellow Class D,
we're on even footing with you.
Even footing, huh?
You just don't get it.
We've got plenty of
options if we want 'em.
We don't need to put up
with bullshit, y'know?
They seem to have noticed the special
weapon unique to the first-years.
Just what method do you expect to use?
You get it, right?
We've got a way to force the scores down.
What? Gimme a damn break!
If you slack off on the test,
your ass is expelled!
Yeah, if we do it by slacking off.
But we can refuse to pair
up until the day of the test
and force a penalty that way.
Since only second-years can be expelled,
that hurts you way more than us.
Even if you aren't expelled,
won't you face a loss of private points?
Yeah, but that's a small price
compared to the one you'll pay.
Right?
Yes. A three-month loss of private
points is 240,000 points at most.
I don't see it as a fatal issue.
You get the situation now?
Get your head outta your ass.
Keep your head, Sudo-kun.
You know how things work
at this school, don't you?
Yeah, fine.
Guess there's not much
muscle on that big frame.
I barely even touched you.
You son of a—
What are you doing?!
Ishizaki!
The cockroaches keep comin'
outta the woodwork.
You'd better back off the smack
talk on the second-years!
If you want to get out of here alive,
you should lay off, Ishizaki.
Wh-Why are you stopping me?
I know you very well.
Hosen... you're quite
a celebrity back home.
Y-You've heard of him, Ryuen-san?
Though I didn't expect him to look
like such a slack-jawed fool.
Fancy meeting you here.
I've heard more than I
ever cared to about you.
But I didn't think the legendary Ryuen
would be such a scrawny little weakling.
And I can see you're all muscle,
right up to the contents of your skull.
I tried a few times to head up
your way and murder your ass,
but you got scared and hid out, I guess.
You were lucky.
If you'd actually found me,
you wouldn't be able to run
your mouth like this now.
How about we settle all
the trash talk right now?
Let's not.
I can't see what I'd gain from
a fistfight with a gorilla.
You're not going to defend us
from the first-years at all?
We can finish this anytime, after all.
Hey, come back and play, Ryuen.
Nah, I don't think so.
In that case...
Just try and get her free!
C'mon, spectators!
You can try me all at once!
Are you insane?
Damn it!
Hosen-kun, stop it now.
The upperclassmen are conscious
of the security cameras.
Going on a rampage here
won't accomplish anything.
Yeah, I know. I'm just playin' around.
If you insist on being reckless,
I'll take actions of my own.
Perhaps I'll make a certain
something common knowledge.
Threatening me takes guts, Nanase.
But if you disappoint me,
you'll pay for it.
When that happens,
I'll be prepared for it.
What's this all about, Hosen?
Fighting shouldn't be done in the streets.
This doesn't qualify as a fight.
Let's go, Nanase.
That seems wise.
I'm ready to pair up when you're
ready to grovel, Ryuen-paisen.
Unfortunately, I don't pair
up with wild gorillas.
What a shame.
See ya, Horikita.
I'm sorry for the trouble.
She was sizing me up.
Classroom of the Elite 4th Season 2nd Year 1st Term